the travel industry is going to go
through some major changes in the next
few months even years and we as
travelers need to be prepared for this
you see we have seen chaos and heartache
in the news and it is going to take us a
while until we gain back our confidence
to travel again and if we're thinking
that our travel is going to be anything
like it was those pre-pandemic days it
is not going to be that way at all we
are definitely going to be seeing some
major modifications in the way that we
travel what are those changes going to
look like in the future well for
instance take the airlines they have
already started implementing deep
cleaning and fumigation in between
flights and we know that this needed to
happen how many of you out there already
get on a plane and start cleaning off
the area your table your chair your
armrest everything before you touch it I
do I did a video on that as well because
we know that airlines and aircrafts are
one of the dirtiest places out there so
we knew that this had to come in to
affect their turnover between a flight
coming in and a flight going out was way
too short so they definitely needed to
make adjustments there and they have
already started to do that also with the
airlines when the time comes that the
pandemic has been called off and the
airports are open now they're not going
to have all of their fleet ready to go
no aircrafts need to be maintained on a
daily basis and so an airline's has to
allocate a small amount of their
aircraft in their fleet to be maintained
on a regular basis because it's very
expensive to have that done all the time
so they can't do their entire fleet so
when the day comes that they say borders
are now open airports are ready to go
aircrafts will only have a small amount
of those ready to start flying again and
get back into
halation it's gonna meet the demands of
the traveler well possibly because
actually as we go forward the travelers
out there are going to be a little bit
more cautious about traveling I mean
none of us know if there's going to be a
resurgence of this virus or a variation
of it and because of that many of us
will want to travel closer to home we
don't want to be caught out of a country
in case the borders end up closing again
we've got fresh memories and so we don't
want that to happen to us but in saying
that how many of us have been affected
financially we probably won't even have
the finances to even make travel a
priority I mean we still have bills that
have to be paid maybe they've been
deferred but they still need to be paid
our savings has been depleted some of us
have already had to take money out of
our pensions and so no definitely
travel not necessarily going to be
something that we're going to be
thinking about right off the bat so it's
gonna take us a while as travelers to
get those numbers back up there again
it's kind of funny actually I did a
video not that long ago on / tourism and
you know at that time there was way too
much travel to certain destinations and
it was too much for the people who lived
there to take on now because there is no
travel and there is no tourist there to
these areas at all
they are also affected financially as
well all the way down to the souvenir
shop so no it's not all just about the
airline's losing money or the hotels or
their restaurants it's about the little
mom posh shop as well that has actually
been affected financially by this travel
ban cruise ships oh my gosh cruise ships
is going to take a long time for them to
gain our confidence and for us to feel
comfortable to get back on the ship and
they definitely have to make some major
changes to their operations right now
we've seen some horrific stories of the
ships that have been stranded and people
who've been sick and dying on these
ships that they are just like floating
petri dishes
so it will take the cruise line industry
a long time to get us back on board
again so what are the changes they're
gonna make oh well I'll just have to
wait and see on that one but they are
coming and we know as an industry they
will be making those changes another
area that we've already started to see
changes on is the travel insurance so
it's all may be well and good that you
want to book a trip take a look at your
travel insurance it is not going to be
the same and it has already started to
make changes from the time that they
announced that there was this Cobra 19
outbreak to the time that they started
closing the borders in the airports we
have already seen changes being made in
the policy wording and the language of
your travel insurance policies and
that's because trip cancellations they
were taken off the table first if you
were taking out a policy after it was
announced it was no longer valid
emergency health anybody who took a
policy out after it was announced again
about kovat 19 and travel you would not
have been covered if you were away and
contracted Kovan 19 or if you had any
association with that virus going
forward some of the companies have
already changed their language in that
they will not cover you for kovat 19 or
any other pandemic and the reason they
put that in there is because kovat 19 is
the virus as we know it today but as it
mutates and as it changes they may very
well end up changing the name thereby
it's all in their language they will not
cover you for that and this is only the
beginning these are only a few companies
and when one does they all do so you're
going to need to pay close attention to
your policy wording when you do take out
a travel insurance policy basically what
we have done is we have pressed the
reset button it's not entirely a bad
thing but it's unfortunate that it took
a catastrophe like this for us to wake
up and realize that we have been taking
advantage of our planet and that we have
had some really poor global practices
and they needed to be amended to our
health care work
who are working diligently 24/7 out
there saving lives putting their own
lives on the line and taking care of our
sick thank you thank you so much you are
deeply deeply appreciated changes are
going to come about on a global level I
don't think in history that we have ever
seen anything like this and it's pretty
exciting and I'm looking forward to it
and I'm also looking forward to seeing
you again here next week
adios stay safe and remember we are all
one